Podcasting 2.0 for August 20th, 2021,
episode 51, preserve, protect, and extend.
That's right, Batman.
Hello, everybody.
Time once again for your weekly
board meeting of Podcasting 2.0.
Everything happening at podcastindex.org
and podcastindex.social.
I'm Adam Curry in the heart of Hill
Country, Texas, and in Alabama.
He's a phenom in the art
of first in, first out.
My friend on the other end,
ladies and gentlemen, Dave Jones.
It's not Boostergram week,
it's Boostergram month.
Yeah.
It's off the chain, man.
People are throwing
Boostergrams everywhere.
We had some kind of breakthrough, man.
Like, all of a sudden,
podcasting got super fun.
Yeah, it did.
It's like, wow, it works.
One little loop.
If you're brand new to the board meeting,
we're talking about the Boostergrams,
which now allow you to
send a payment with a
message to the podcaster of your choosing,
while listening, or if you want, to the
entire team, or to any of the individuals.
You could even say, hey, great
app, and boost the app developer.
And it's, and for me, they come
in on email. You set that up.
I love that. It's the first
thing I look at in the morning.
I look at the, yeah, sure, the
Boostergrams. It's fantastic.
Yeah, I'm wondering how people are going,
what people are doing right
now for their own node.
Like, you know, I'm
wondering how people are
getting those Boostergrams off their node,
because we, I mean, there's
a couple of scripts.
I've got one out there, and John Chigi
wrote a Python script that'll pull stuff.
Oh, I've got to put
that in the show notes.
Send that to me, and
I'll put it in the show.
Is that on the GitHub?
Yeah. It's called Extract
TLV is the name of the repo.
And so, but I don't know
that anybody's using it.
So, like Dave Jackson, for
instance, I'm not sure,
I don't think he can even get
his Boostergrams out of there.
Now, does he have his, he
has his own node, right?
Yeah, he's got a voltage node.
And we have to stop right here.
Just say, holy crap, Dave Jackson.
History is rhyming.
History is rhyming like hip-hop.
I've got clips. I've got
clips of Dave Jackson.
So, Dave Jackson showed, now,
I don't remember exactly,
because there was a lot of people
and a lot of things happening,
but I believe Dave Jackson started the
School of Podcasting pretty early on.
And he, and, you know, he's
one of these people, like,
we have so many in the Podcasting
2.0, here it comes, community.
You know, we've got Christopher Issein,
who's a, you know, is a feed finder.
The Swedish trickler.
The Swedish trickler, exactly.
We, you know, of course, all of our app
developers, but we've got all these,
these specialized little things.
And, you know, when it comes to
teaching people how to do it,
I think Dave was the OG,
from what I can remember.
And it was School of Podcasting,
but he was, he was, he was,
he's just that kind of guy.
And so, for him to jump in and
say, all right, what is it called?
What is it?
Leading the Bleeding.
Yeah, Leading the Bleeding.
The first episode.
Great show name, by the way.
Yeah.
First episode, what is this, Satoshi?
It's fantastic.
Yeah, I think it's great.
It's a good show, good show name.
And he, he couldn't stop teaching
even in that first episode.
I mean, he was, he was still like,
he, he just, he's going on Bitcoin.
These just swerves into, you
know, a pay podcaster, you know,
you don't do this or your
show's going to suck.
Well, but that was also, it's so
reminiscent of Podcasting 1.0.
And, you know, we'd all be swerving.
We didn't know what, you
know, we knew, but, you know,
we go all over the place and
we talk about, at the time,
and this still comes back in any, any
scholastic work about podcasting.
But certainly the consultants
in podcasting will say, well,
you have to be passionate, you know,
so there was a lot of, you know,
what to do, what was it, you
know, how do you do a show?
There was a lot of that.
And in addition to, you know, hosting
and all that stuff and comments,
in many ways the same, but,
you know, with some added,
there's added bits in here,
which is just fantastic.
I want to talk about that for a
second, because I dug into this,
let me see if I can find, this
paper that Spotify released,
and I think Pridlin is the
one that linked it at first.
It's called Spotify Language
for Listener Engagement.
Oh, yes, I did see the posting.
I did not read it.
Modeling Language Usage and
Listener Engagement in Podcasts.
I will tell you, this is the most boring
thing I have read in a long time.
It is incredibly dry.
But I read the entire thing for you.
Thank you.
So I don't have to.
Beautiful.
Yes, I did it for you.
What did we learn, Dave Jones?
I just had this feeling there might be some
interesting things in here on a hunch.
And so we learned, let's see, here's
the nitty gritty on this thing.
It's on page something.
It says, so here's sort
of their findings, okay?
It says, you'll see, number one,
the correlation between ads
and engagement is mixed.
Large amounts of ads and transcripts are
associated with lower engagement in all but
the bottom popularity
quartile, whatever that means.
It's a quartile.
The bottom 25%.
Okay, all right.
Ads and descriptions, on the other hand,
do not hurt engagement on the whole and,
in fact, are associated with higher
engagement in the top quartile.
So, yeah, you're going
to sleep, aren't you?
Yeah.
So, a couple of things on that.
Ads and chapter links.
Hello.
Make sense.
Yeah, totally.
Especially for PI stuff, like per inquiry.
Mm-hmm.
Like, you know, where
people say, use this code.
You can say, just tap on the link
because it includes the code in the URL.
Yeah.
I mean, so if the ads and descriptions don't
hurt and the ads in the audio do hurt,
well, then, you know, this is perfect.
And then you get, you don't have to
even, you don't even have to do,
what do they call it?
Coupon codes.
Yeah, exactly.
It's all in the link.
Yeah, just, you just tap it right there.
Kaboom.
So, that was the first thing.
Okay, solved.
Okay, Spotify.
How can we fix them next?
This was, this was like,
this looks like a very
intense research project
that somebody got paid lots of money for.
And I think we just solved this
in about a minute and a half.
Was it Deloitte?
Deloitte.
These are some hardcore
computer science geeks
because they use words
that I had to look up.
Oh, goodness.
The, but here, okay, so here's,
here's two things that I thought were
interesting and I'll tell you why.
High engagement podcasts are less likely
to contain interjection and swearing and
high engagement podcast creators
tend to speak relatively fast.
Okay, so the high engagement
podcasters are less
likely to contain
interjection and swearing.
Well, what does, what
does engagement mean?
Engagement surely means
people buying something.
What does it mean?
Commenting where?
You know, what does high, I just,
this is my problem with the term.
The engagement is.
Is there a definition in this paper?
There is a definition and it is
something that I probably highlighted,
but I cannot find.
That's all right.
Since many, no, that's not it.
No, I don't know.
It's fuzzy.
If you can't tell me.
Oh, here it is.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
That's it.
I got it.
Stream rate.
Let's see.
Our metric of engagement is stream rate,
which we define as the proportion
of first-time listeners
who listen for at least five minutes.
That's their, that's their, that's
their definition of engagement.
So it says where a listener's decision to
continue listening for as long as five
minutes is likely to be
influenced by the content.
Therefore, it's engagement.
Is that, is that anything like what
you would consider engagement?
Also, what I'm hearing them say is
if you, if someone, a new listener,
so not a current listener, but a new
listener listens for five minutes,
then engagement is a metric of
uptake and growth of the podcast.
Not, not, not of, uh, people hearing, uh,
or of the advertising
being effective or of,
of people engaging with the
brand or advertising content.
It's new people.
Does that sound right to you?
I think so.
Cause they specifically say that.
Who cares?
It says, uh, large, it says large amounts
of ads in transcripts are associated with
lower engagement in all, but
the bottom popularity quartile.
While this may be explained by the fact
that many listeners skip ads in the audio
stream, if the effect is strong enough to
indicate that ads seem to hurt engagement,
even though surveys report that
most listeners don't mind the ads.
I've always, I'm glad we read that
because that means when I hear other,
you know, podcasts or
read about engagement, I,
I did not have that in
mind as the definition.
So it's, it's for growth of your podcast.
How many people go like,
oh, okay, I'm listening.
You could, you could do engagement
per episode, I guess that's okay too,
but, but all right.
So is this about, this is all very gross.
Is this about advertising or
is it about growing your show?
As, as I've heard said so often, by the
way, do you want to know how many lists,
do you want to know how
many listeners we have?
How do you know?
I don't, I was just kidding.
That's good.
You don't know.
I will challenge any statistic
you throw at me, Dave Jones.
Well, I don't even have a number.
I have no clue.
Well, this, this actually
brings up a good point.
A few weeks ago, you wrote a blog
post, which, what was it called?
Oh, the blog, the, it's time to drop
the egos and address the IP addresses.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly.
And, and you wrote this and you
sent it and Tina did her Tina wash.
Uh, we all looked at it.
Uh, we all thought it was great.
Uh, you held back for a week and then you
posted it and it was like, it wasn't,
it wasn't a lot of uptake, but I believe
it was, uh, a very great influence on,
uh, Brian Barletta's,
uh, IP addresses story.
Yeah, I think so.
And we're, and me, so I worked with Dan
Benjamin for quite a few months of back and
forth to come up with the
framework for all that.
Uh, and, uh, you know,
he had this initial idea and we just
kept refining it and refining it down.
And, uh, then, uh, Cridlin gave us some
critical feedback about three weeks ago.
And so then we added one more, one last
piece to get sort of over the hump.
And then, uh, and then we published it.
And so me and Dan are going to be
on the sounds profitable show, uh,
I think next week, next Wednesday.
Ah, good, good.
Because, um, you know, I saw that you
had several solutions and I think, uh,
that, that we don't have to get
into, into great depth about it.
Cause if you're going to do that with,
uh, on pod land or it sounds profitable,
then I definitely want you to do it there.
Um, but it seems like there was, you know,
a solution that you offered
a technical solution
that could be implemented on the app side.
And then there was the one
that I favor, of course,
which is the actual listening statistics.
Even if you're sending one sat per minute
or even pretend or per five minutes to
assure continued engagement.
Yeah.
See that?
I mean, that's clearly the one I prefer
as well, because then you have, uh,
then you have actual numbers and they're
protect the stats or protected the listener
privacy protected by
the lightning network.
And we already have statistics, you know,
statistically, I think we have enough,
um, pod, uh, podcast apps.
And people that we could draw some,
not, maybe not for every podcast,
we should be able to
draw some conclusions.
Well, this goes back to the, to
the whole thing that like this,
this keeps coming back
up over and over again.
When through, throughout all of podcasting
2.0 so far is this notion that you can't
get the industry on the whole.
And this is why I thought, uh, Barletta's
interview on pod land was really good.
Hold on.
I have a clip.
Ah, okay.
Now I have a clip of his conclusion,
which is what kind of saddened me,
but hopefully, uh, you and I
can set everyone straight.
His, when James asked
him, so what are you,
Brian Barletta going to do
about the fact that Apple,
I think that's the main issue here.
Apple is going to start
obfuscating IP addresses.
So tracking and the, um,
uh, the, uh, the ad,
the podcast ad industry
will hurt it severely.
This is pretty much the
only way that things can
be tracked at all for some accountability.
Uh, and there's, uh, there's an
entire industry built on it.
And so his answer just made me sad.
So what are we going to do about it?
Brian Barletta, what are
you going to do about it?
Oh God.
I think, I think, uh, I grew
up a little bit in this year.
I think that it was very fun to, to,
to yell about all these things and to tell
people about all these things and try and
idealistically come at it.
I have not been the
biggest fan of the IAB,
but the truth is that they're the only
one organizing everyone in this room.
So I have joined the tech lab and I've
joined the audio committee and I'm going to
talk to every single person I can.
I'm going to reach out and continue to
talk with Apple, Google, Spotify, Amazon,
and I'm going to advocate
for all of them to just
come to the table and build a framework.
We're past the point of rad, the, you
know, the listening spec that NPR created.
I think that we need to look
at the core functionality.
I think we need to safeguard the
base analytics of podcasting.
We need to acknowledge that as an
industry, we do still revolve around RSS.
We find such value in
the open nature of it.
If IP address wants to go away,
I think every single person in podcasting
would raise their hand in support of that.
If we do not lose the metrics on
the hosting and publisher side.
So this is my invitation.
I will gladly play shepherd.
I will gladly play matchmaker and do
whatever I have to do to get everyone at the
table to just figure out how we do this.
And maybe how we're the first industry in
advertising to abandon IP address ahead of
the curb to show people
how it's done once again.
Wow.
That'll be fascinating.
Where can we read more of this
if we want to find out more?
Yeah.
Soundsprofitable.com.
And you can find the newsletter.
You can find the podcast.
You can find the product deep dives where
I go over how all these different amazing
ad tech products work.
And at the end of the day,
I just want to say that ad tech and
podcasting is the entire technology stack.
Because every aspect of it
can help people advertise.
So this is really important.
Advertising will survive.
These core metrics are critical to
everybody who does baked in ads,
to not even doing ads, to doing Patreon
or self-funded, or to just do it for fun.
So this is critical to everybody.
And I hope everybody gets involved.
You're much closer to this than I am.
But I just want to make a
couple remarks up front.
First of all, I love his energy.
And that kind of energy, I want to
focus it where it's beneficial.
Broadcasting 2.0 is not mutually
exclusive with advertising.
And I think there's ways we can help.
And then the third thing,
which is what I know you as.
Let me stop on the third thing.
We've known each other
for a long time, Dave.
And I always knew that if we did
something together that took off,
I knew it would be a lot of fun.
And it's really a lot of fun.
It is.
I really love doing this shit with you.
All right.
And three, this is the approach that has
resulted in nothing for over a decade.
The approach is you have an entire
army of developers, podcasters,
listeners who can support any type of
implementation that we come up with.
And these other guys, they
will have to adapt to us.
But this is, you're a little more
eloquent in explaining that.
Oh, and then I guess 3A,
Apple doesn't care about you.
Yeah.
No, I thought about 3A a couple of times.
You know, listening to that, I thought,
well, you know, Apple doesn't care.
And then, and they just really
don't, they just really don't.
I mean, I guess I'd push back a little bit
and say, it's not really even a pushback.
I guess I would say that,
I mean, this is, that's,
that's what we expect Brian to do.
Brian, that's, that's where
he's, that's where he's living.
Oh, sure.
You know, he's living.
And so, and, and he's on that
side, uh, or that side of things.
And then we're on the grass,
you know, sort of the fat, the,
the lower, the grassroots.
Then we need to give him ammunition
when he goes into battle.
Yeah.
That's exactly what I was thinking.
That's a great, see, that's the, that's the
better way to say that because we're in
the perfect example is Dave Jackson
launching a show, uh, about, you know,
about value for
value also Evo Tara this week,
uh, had a great episode and, uh,
I got a clip of, of Evo.
I have an opinion.
Is that the clip?
Uh, yeah.
Hit that.
When it comes to what you prefer,
you recommend people utilize to enjoy
your show, just like that server above.
I think you as a podcaster should have an
opinion on which app someone should use.
Which are the best ones.
Yeah.
Oh, before I forget.
Here's your cue to boost.
You know, you want to.
That shit works people.
And send, uh, and send, uh, Evo a boost.
He's, his podcast on
pontifications podcast.
He's, he's value for value too.
And, and once we get, uh,
I saw you in the good hub.
Once we get the episode, uh, value blocks,
we're going to be able
to put that in, right?
Yeah.
We can put that in.
So excited.
So like, that's where I'm thinking about
this is we are already, and I say we,
I mean, podcasting 2.0 as a movement is
already pushing back on these things.
And, uh, like we, I had a long winter
back and forth this week with, uh, uh,
with Mark Asquith from Captivate and then
Tom Webster jumped in and, uh, it was,
it's all sparked by Evo's, uh,
Evo's episode, which was fantastic.
It was a, the typical thing that
we have been hearing for a while.
It was, well, you know,
there's gotta be some sort of
critical mass and you've got to get
everybody to play along.
And, uh, you know, it was just
this, the same sort of, you know,
you have to get, uh, you
have to get momentum in order,
or you have to get size before
any of this will, will matter.
And, you know, that, that is
the toxic part of what we've,
of what podcasting has to deal
with on a constant basis.
And I mean, I understand what they're
trying to get at, but the, the,
the game has changed though.
Now there is, now there's a group of people
that are inspired to see change happen.
And once that, once that becomes reality,
once there are a group of
people who are inspired
for, for change, just change, it
doesn't matter what the change is.
If they, they want to see
things improve and things
be different and they want to see new
things, once that becomes,
there's a hunger for that,
then that thing becomes a life of its own.
It takes on a life of its
own and it can, it can,
it can make things happen that couldn't
happen before when there was
nobody there to advocate for it.
This is okay.
So the analog couple of things,
what we had in 1.0 and what we're
missing in 2.0 probably is transmitters.
We don't need no stinking transmitters.
It was against the established media,
not like it was a fight or anything,
but it was like, Hey, look at this.
There's a back door.
We're going around them.
So that was, that's kind of what that was.
And the pirate radio type field.
Yes, exactly.
And so now it's a different
situation because the, uh, you know,
Apple is one of the OG pirates,
but you know, the pirate is, you know,
stopped caring because there was no loot,
you know, kept looking for the map
and you know, where's the exit?
I can't, I can't find the gold doubloons.
And so, you know, they don't care.
Then in came another pirate, a
true pirate, which is Spotify.
And, and they went, ha, we
don't see a map either, but ha,
give us your doubloons podcasters.
Yeah.
And, and we're like, well,
you got to get all the podcasters
to have the doubloons, but
that's not how it works.
It's just, it's, it's the nature
of a decentralized system.
It, it, it's gosh, you know, it's like
what, um, a bit like Max Kaiser said, uh,
in Austin, you know, Bitcoin
was designed to be attacked.
RSS in a way was designed to be attacked.
It's a honey badger.
It's like, huh?
Tumbles on, you know,
there's no advocacy group.
There's no, I was once in the RSS
board and I got kicked off because
I, you know, I don't know.
I did.
I missed 18,000 meetings
that went to spam.
You missed a meeting?
Oh yeah.
Hard to believe.
No, I don't really miss meetings.
Actually.
I'm pretty good at that.
Uh, but I don't do them anymore
or at least I try not to.
Um, so yeah, so we have such, um,
I can feel the network effect
and it comes when you get
embeddable players that are showing
chapters and someone says, oh, oh, hold on.
What was, uh, what is that again?
What's the just cast?
I think just cast.
I think that's what it is.
And you see that it's like, oh
wow, that's kind of interesting.
And well, you might as well pop this now.
Um, because with a little bit of luck,
we're kind of early development cycle.
I think it was two shows ago we
were talking, I was again, uh, Oh,
it was with Stephen B.
Was that three shows ago?
Two or three shows ago.
Don't ask me that.
I don't know.
Um, I was saying, oh, you
know, my, my old thing,
if I really want to be able to create
a new episode right in the app.
And of course, uh, all of a sudden
Stephen says, oh, check this out.
Oh yeah.
That was a chat.
He takes that as a direct challenge.
Yeah.
Well, um, so today if all goes well, if,
if we're fortunate and
you're hearing this, it
doesn't necessarily mean
that, um, that you,
if nothing else changed and you're hearing
the show, then it probably worked.
And this is really cool
because you're looking at, um,
a curio caster and you know, there's
an ad episode and you
click on the ad episode
and it copies over a
whole bunch of the, the
metadata you already had, but it's all
the tags, almost all the tags, uh,
right down to the feed meta
tags for funding, et cetera.
And it's got a nice little editor for
show notes and you, um, you click,
you don't even click save.
You just click, oh yeah,
you click export RSS and it poops
out an RSS file that doesn't
even change the generator, uh, meta
tag, which is, God have mercy.
So I had, I, I, I got
the link for this and I
couldn't get it to work and I think it was
just a browser problem.
You can't use it on mobile.
Okay.
So I haven't seen, I
haven't seen how it works.
Like, I don't know anything.
You have to tell me how it works
because I haven't even used it.
How can that be?
You didn't get the link?
No, I got the link, but it wouldn't
work in my browser on desktop.
I think it, maybe it was brave.
Every time I would click the episode
thing, it would just not do anything.
So you didn't get an empty box.
No, no, I didn't.
But that may have been a, uh, he
may have been doing something.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
That can happen.
Especially with web apps.
Yeah.
No, it's, you know, so
basically it's a template
and it's got a drop down
on the right hand side.
So you know, your top things are,
you know, title, episode number, uh,
show notes, URL for
enclosure for the MP3 file.
So, I mean, that part is still
manual, but that's how I do it now.
Anyway, I just FTP it into our system,
both the feed, the MP3 and, um, the, uh,
a temporary SRT file that
says transcript processing.
Come back soon, y'all.
By the way, I don't think you said,
I think you said Steven B and, um,
don't make, some people may not understand
that he's the developer of CurioCaster.
So this is all happening
in the CurioCaster app.
Yes.
Yes, exactly.
And so if you look at the
CurioCaster app on the desktop,
it's three panes and the middle
one is the episode list.
That's what this, what this link
you doesn't work for you pops up.
Click on new episode and you
get a blank box at the top.
And as you're filling stuff out
on the, in the right hand panel,
which turns into like
a templatized, uh, like a WordPress type
thing, you know, and you're filling out the
basics, you see it appear in the, in the
new episode, uh, in your podcast list.
So you actually can preview
it right there in the app.
Okay.
So is it live yet or is it
still in the beta site?
Oh no, it's that link that I gave you.
No, that's the beta site.
So then once you do that
and it copies over all
the fields that you
don't want to be typing
in every single time, um, in fact,
I think you can have it copy
everything over, just make
a duplicate and change whatever you want.
Um, man, this is like, I know you well
enough to know that you are salivating.
Dude, I'm jizzing over here.
This is crazy.
Yeah.
And then you have a dropdown for all
the different tags and everything.
And after the show, uh, I want to sit with
you and go through it and make sure we've
got all the, all that I'm
doing all the tags, right.
Cause I've never even used any of these.
Okay.
So, okay.
So what we need now is, is a,
a hosting company to allow an,
for an API to express an API that
can handle this thing.
So, yeah, well, isn't that,
can't we hook into the,
like what pod press does with blueberry?
Yes.
I'm thinking, um, um, blueberry, um,
is the one that pops to mind
first because they seem
to have the infrastructure for this.
Um, but I'm thinking that,
I mean, this makes sense,
makes sense to me for other hosts to
build out an API for this, if they
don't have one, because then you can,
there's a new, this
feels like a new class of app where
you're going to have, I mean,
just to be clear, if
people aren't following
what we're talking about.
It's so clear to me and I'm, and I'm
like, why don't people see my vision?
Well, the, the, the idea
here is that you're,
you're creating your
podcast feed in the same
app that you're consuming the feed
with, which is kind of a crazy idea.
But so like you're, it's
like going, I mean,
you're going into your
podcast app to listen
to podcasts, but then you
go to your podcast and you,
there's an episode episode and then
it gives you a feed.
So I'm thinking that, but it's really,
it's really appropriate on the desktop.
That's where it really comes to life.
Mobile is, you know, can't
see that being necessary,
but you could create
your own scripts, even
an Apple script, you know, when you,
when you save an RSS feed into
this folder, boom, it goes off.
There's a million ways to do it.
The self-hosters will love this.
Yeah.
This is, uh, and that's the, that's,
so that's the next step is
you've got now, okay, now
you got to feed, you got to stick it
somewhere and you've got audio files.
You need to stick them somewhere.
So then that's where the host, a hosting
company could come in and have an API that
would let CurioCaster just
plug into this dude's
account so that they can just go done
right, right to, right
to the hosting company.
And it, and it just gives
them the data where
the hosting company can suck
it in and build the feed out.
And now the app developers can start
offering these services for different,
uh, hosting companies and you know,
they should get a VIG for that.
Yeah.
That'd be awesome.
Right.
That's it.
I mean, now, now we have an ecosystem.
Now we're all talking to each other.
We've all been so gosh dang it independent
except for the hosting and podcaster.
They're bringing the, the, the apps can
now bring customers directly to the host.
Yeah.
Hey, you want to start your own?
Click here.
Use this app.
Yeah.
You're in the, you're in the app.
Well, you know what that is?
That's anchor.
Yeah.
Only everyone gets to do it
and everyone participates.
Yes.
It's decentralized anchor is what it is.
Oh, there you go.
You get, you get, you're
listening to some stuff
and you flip over and it's like, oh,
I want to start a pot.
Well, you know what?
I want to start a podcast too.
New episode.
Yes.
Exactly.
Bam.
New episode.
And then it pops up like,
which host do you want to use?
Blueberry, Buzzsprout, RSS.com,
Captivate, Trent, you know,
just gives you a list of all the
participating hosts and you say, yeah.
And they're like, okay, well,
you know, we'll get, we'll, uh,
you could do a signup and then
the app developer gets a percentage
off, off the signup or whatever.
And discount codes that podcasters
read out is so 2010, bro.
It is.
It's like, oh yeah, that's right.
Oh man.
We're making everybody
money but ourselves, Dave.
No, no.
We've got booster grams.
Well, hold on.
We'll get to the booster grams.
Um, so along with this comes
our rejiggered positioning,
which you kind of came up with
it and we, we, uh, moved
a few words around,
but I want to share it because
I really, really like it.
And this is such an
excellent example of it.
Podcast Index is here
to preserve, protect,
and extend the open
independent podcast ecosystem.
Do this by enabling
developers to have access to
an open categorized index that will always
be available for free for any use.
Try a new podcast app today and see
how much better the experience can be.
And right now, and that just
links to the, to the apps page,
which is all going to change,
but at least we're figuring out what
the hell we're going to change.
We know, we know it's
going to look pretty.
We're just figuring out all these pieces
and all these proper positionings.
And this is good though.
I like this a lot.
And it's exactly what we're doing.
Preserve, protect, and extend.
It just, it felt the, the original mission
statement that was up there about,
uh, preserving free speech
and that kind of thing.
It, it felt, uh, incomplete and just,
it was too simplistic and it was just,
it was, let me, I think
I can say this better.
It was so simplistic
that it was easy to just
get triggered by it for political reasons.
And it did not fully express what
we were actually trying to do.
Agreed.
And to be fair to
ourselves, when we started,
there was only two things
we were going to do.
We're going to have an independent index
that any app developer could tap into,
and we're going to make
lightning work with Satoshis.
And what came out of that is
like, like we uncorked some,
some bottle of pent up, uh, creativity
and energy, and it just spewed out
a whole namespace with, you know,
with tons of, of new features and ideas.
Uh, that's, you just described
a Fauci boost, I think.
Boost!
There we go.
That's, that's exactly
what happened, yeah.
So, so this is where I feel
bad because, you know,
we started the boost
again, boost a gram craze.
You know, we've been pushing it real hard.
We've been active participants in it, uh,
Cridlin asked me to do a jingle for their
boost a gram corner, and
I completely forgot.
And then he called me out on, on the
show after they had a, a boost a gram,
a bukkake fest of just, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
You said that, that is,
that is, uh, is a foul.
That is inappropriate.
I'm sorry.
But it's what it was.
I mean, I was there, I was like,
Oh, this, listen to these guys.
They're going nuts.
And after they just did this
whole bit on how fucked that, um,
how messed up advertising
is, it's trying to be good now.
Uh, you know, they go straight into,
they were so joyous and so
happy and they made like
$130 in satoshis from booster grams.
Like this, this is, I had
a big smile on my face.
Oh, I did too.
You can do it now, do they?
Yeah, that's what I was thinking.
I was thinking I'll do
a live jingle for them.
Do it live.
Yeah, we'll do it live, baby.
Let me see if I can, let
me see if I can do this.
Okay.
And so it's boost a gram corner.
All right.
Yeah.
Now it's time for the boost, boost,
boost, boost, boost, boost, boost, boost,
boost, boost, boost a gram corner.
It's too much.
Too much?
No.
You, you, you unloaded everything
in the arsenal on that one.
I got, okay.
Coach me, coach me.
I was expecting background singers.
Coach me, coach me, coach me.
Just simple.
Just, you know, just, you know,
just like a big booming voice.
It's like, uh, or I can do
in a world where podcast
news matters more than women
with comfortable shoes.
It's your boost a gram corner.
I think you need to go with top 40.
I think you need to top 40.
Top 40.
Yeah.
I mean, they're both radio guys.
You need to go solid top 40.
That's what I was doing.
I was doing like boost a gram.
Boost a gram.
Boost a gram corner.
Let me try that one.
Let me try it.
Boost a boost a boost a gram.
Boost a gram.
Boost a gram corner.
Can't get more top 40 than that.
But I'll just do a big voice.
All right.
Here we go.
Do it.
Do a straight, do a straight, yeah.
Do your best Casey Kasem.
And now boost a gram corner.
No, no, that sucks.
Don't do that.
That's my Casey Kasem.
Okay.
I didn't mean Casey Kasem.
And now a long distance
dedication about a dead puppy.
Do your best Dalala.
Yeah.
All right.
Here we go.
Boost a gram corner.
No, that's boring.
I like the other one better.
All right.
Well, they can choose and
edit whatever they want.
I think I've done enough.
I've done my business.
I have returned as the pod father.
Yes.
Heard you on the survival podcast.
That was really good.
Oh, thanks.
Yeah.
My audio was going berserk.
And I mean, I barely had any idea
what I was saying half the time.
Well, it didn't come across that way.
It's so nice.
And it's another reason why
I love working with you.
You know, from the early days on
where I was dragging a spark Voyager,
which was the sun luggable workstation.
Did it have a detachable keyboard with it?
Yes, sir.
I had a color.
Yeah, the color LCD screen
with a built-in modem.
And I dragged that thing into the office
of the CEO of Reebok and Budweiser.
And I jacked their fax machine and
had a 100-foot cord, telephone cord.
And we'd bring up Mosaic and
say, here's the future sun.
But it was pretty much always me.
And I was MTV guy.
So I was like, hey, monkey
boy here to dance show.
He's a minute of that.
Yeah, everybody.
That's been my career for a
long time until, you know,
podcasting and really no agenda and
we're doing podcasting 2.0.
So now there's someone who tells the
story in an even better way than I do.
You're so calm and you are very, very, I'm
taking some lessons from how you do that.
No, I enjoy this show because
I can feed off your energy.
My natural state is very…
You're very NPR-ish, but
without the annoying uptalk.
Oh, thank you.
Well, you were on Alison
Morrow's show too, right?
Yeah.
I'm about three-quarters
of the way through it.
Yeah, it was fun.
I like her.
I want to get her on Value for Value.
Oh, that'd be good.
She'll need work, though.
She's coming straight out of mainstream,
so she's got some learning to do.
But she's, I had no, I
didn't, I knew about her.
I think we might have covered her
story on No Agenda a long time ago.
But I got all kinds of interesting
messages from, you know, Sir Gene.
He's like, oh, you were great on Alison.
Like, you watch Alison?
Oh, yeah, since episode five.
Like, oh.
I'd never even heard of her until you
said you were going to be on her show.
But I watched enough to see the chat.
And the chat was, I've never really seen,
I mean, I've seen the YouTube chat.
I mean, don't get me wrong, but,
like, I've never gotten engaged.
Oh, so you got a live experience.
Yeah, and it was actually really cool.
I can see why people want that.
Yeah, that's what I call engagement.
That can be engagement when
people are doing that stuff,
especially if each chat message
comes with a Satoshi.
It's just like, I mean,
it's like a little troll room on
the side of the screen, you know.
I mean, that's what it feels
like, just a little chat room.
And I can see that.
Hey, so if you took the concept
of a boost, and maybe just,
I'm just going crazy here.
If you took a boostagram, but the message
was, you know, because a boostagram,
the app automatically
should get, you know, just with any
boostagram, the app gets one Sat,
which means the app also
gets the TLV record, right?
And there's a couple of other
people who get the TLV record.
Can that also not constitute
a post, a comment?
Could the app then not say, oh,
that's a comment, and click,
I'll put it right here underneath
the show in the app?
Yeah, I mean, that's the
Sphinx model, right?
Yeah, you're just passing a,
you're passing a Satoshi, I mean,
the Sphinx chat model is
you pass a Satoshi around
with the TLV attached to it.
Right, but how do the other, how do
the other apps get a hold of that?
Could then the, the app that received
that, that comment, uh, then share that?
You'd have to, uh, the first, okay,
so the things that pop out
to me would be like, you
first would possibly take that incoming
message, or that incoming Satoshi.
Hold on a second, Stephen B., don't
build anything yet, just wait.
Yes, please don't do this.
This is, this is really, this is really
unrehearsed, off-the-cuff crap here,
all right, we're being real, yeah.
I feel like we stress people out
when we start talking about this.
Yeah, a lot of people,
I know for sure, yeah.
Yeah, um, so it feels like you could
do it one of two ways, you could,
you could, the
app could get the TLV, so I guess
I'm just envisioning, this is, okay,
so this is YouTube,
and, uh, in this scenario,
this would be something like CurioCaster
or PodFriend that supports video.
Yes, exactly.
And so, it's doing it, it's, it's
seeing it live, and, and on the stream,
the Sats are going to, uh, everybody.
Oh, I already figured it out, stop.
Okay, all right.
All you need is a value block that
is designated for your comments.
Oh.
And, and then you put, so you can,
and then every single payment
that goes there, you just
publish, uh, the comment.
Uh, yeah, what would the publishing
mechanism be like, though?
It's fucking magic, Dave.
I'm surprised you haven't built it yet.
I'm talking about, what is the mechanism?
It's PHP, baby.
Yeah, it's React, it's React Native React.
I don't know what it is.
It's a React component.
Flutter, Flutter solves this.
Spelt.
Um, yeah, no, that, that could work.
You have a dedicated, this is
like the, this is like the chat.
I mean, shoot, we, we, I mean,
I wouldn't mind, I mean,
we could just do that for, for
us, you know, just as a test.
There's something here.
And maybe, maybe the podcaster
services that we're, you know,
that we're working on, maybe
that's something that we could
at least facilitate setting up.
I mean, we don't want to, we
don't want to host anything.
Podcaster services.
That, you're the director
of podcaster services.
Fuck no.
I am the, I am the director
of podcaster success.
Success.
Yes.
It's a podcaster success ninja.
That's, that's what I am.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, this could be, okay.
So the live thing needs to happen first.
Yeah.
Live tag needs to happen first.
That's, that's phase four, baby.
I'm, I'm, I'm declaring it.
I'm planting the flag right now.
Sweet, sweet, sweet.
Because I want it.
Yeah.
And it has to be streaming live.
It can't just be live.
It's got to be streaming live.
Streaming live.
We'll do it through pod, pod ping.
And then, uh, then this would be next.
Yeah.
Pod ping.
Shit.
That's it, Dave.
Pod ping is the answer because pod ping,
although looks like a
centralized service because of
the nature of the blockchain.
It's not, of course, we're going to have
central hubs that build and, you know,
may die or may whatever can happen.
In essence, it continues to be the
mechanism for publishing comments back or,
or just saying, here's, here's
comments for, um, for this GUID, uh,
go to this, um, value block.
Oh, you mean, you mean, you mean, you
mean in the, you mean hot, the hive.
I don't know.
I'm just, cause pod, pod
ping, I'm forget the backend.
I'm just saying pod ping is
a decentralized service,
although it's a centralized
gateway, but we could use pod.
The comments don't go there.
No, not the comments, but, but the,
Hey, here's where the comments live.
This node send to this node, read
from this node, something like that.
I'm not quite sure.
Okay.
I'm shooting around.
So you, so you're saying, uh, you're
saying that you publish the live item,
the live, the app sees it hooks
into the stream, the live stream,
your HLS or whatever.
And it's, you know, it's
pumping the stream out,
but the pod ping that notified the app,
pod ping message that notified the app that
the stream had started also contained a
pointer to where the comments should go.
That is interesting.
Yeah.
That's pretty.
This is why we've been married
for 11 years, darling.
Yeah.
No, don't, no, nobody build this, please.
No, do not.
Martin, Martin, Martin, stop, stop,
stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
No, he's, he's painting this.
He's painting the master bedroom.
Oh, it really is.
Oh, okay.
Well, good.
I'm happy for him.
I know it's, it's a
multi-month process, man.
I, it was same for me.
It was really hard to keep up
with everything and everybody.
So hard.
And then you have kids.
He has a kid now, right?
No, no.
I'm just kidding.
No, he does.
He does have a kid.
I think it's just, isn't
his fiance's child?
I think so.
Oh, I didn't know he had a kid.
Well, congratulations.
I think, well, no, I think
the kid is, is of Disney age.
I don't know.
Martin, I, I.
Get that kid a pod friend mug.
Martin's like, okay, I
gotta turn this down.
My new wife doesn't know about the kid.
The old double wife trip.
I've heard about those Danes.
That doesn't end good.
Oh my goodness.
Um, so, oh, just on the booster grams.
And that was the final thing.
But I just remembered.
Um, I think, I know this was a, a thread
for a moment there on podcast index.social.
Um, but James was reading
a booster gram amounts,
which were after fees and distributions.
And so you're not really getting the
numerology of the, uh, of the boost.
And I think he's getting
it from Satoshi stream.
So where is that?
Or is it, is it an app that
is not sending the right
information or do we even have a
standardized document for this?
I'm not sure we do.
We do.
No, it's yeah.
The, the, that, so Satoshi's.stream
needs to be hooked into the,
it needs to be displaying
the value in the PLV that is
called a value MSAT total.
Yes.
Value underscore MSAT underscore total.
Cause that's the pre that's,
that's the total that was sent
before any fees or anything
before it's been molested.
Before the lightning network
chomped on it like Pac-Man.
That's a good Pac-Man
there's your booster.
There's your booster
gram corner right there.
No.
Uh, but I mean, yeah,
that's, it's in there.
It's in there.
So that Satoshi stream
is not sending is just
displaying the wrong
information or not, or
information different
than, than I expected.
With a complete lack of information, I'm
going to go ahead and blame Satoshi stream.
Okay.
Yeah.
Blame those guys.
Um, so I don't know if, if, if it's
not his problem, then we'll, yeah,
we'll figure it out.
Um, the boost, the.
I was thinking about, about the chapter.
Well, let me just do this.
I need to correct something that I
said on a previous episode because I,
I unintentionally upset the pod love guys.
Oh, uh, because they, we were talking
about pod love chapters, which are in,
which, which are, which is in
the Omni studio feed for, um,
or some NBC podcast or
something that we're
talking Fox podcast.
Yeah.
But, um, they, Andy
thought that I had just,
just screwed that whole thing
up about describing it.
And that was not intentional.
Uh, I just wanted to break
the, I mean, it is, he,
he was upset initially cause
I said it in past tense.
It's like pod love, pod love chapters
was a thing that blah, blah, blah.
That I didn't mean it that way.
It's just, it's just language.
Um, I mean, no pod love
is the pod love chapters
are a spec that is in active
use today in the feed.
And it's just a different, it's
just a different paradigm.
And the whole, the only
reason why we didn't,
because initially we were going
to adopt the pod love chapters.
Yes.
I remember that.
That was the plan.
Uh, but then, you know, two
hosting companies were like, no,
we're not doing that because
they were concerned about feed size.
And so then the natural,
because the chapters go in the
RSS feed in the pod love format.
Got it.
Yeah.
And if you have a hundred
thousand feeds, um, you know,
even in one extra kilobyte per,
you know, per feed can add up.
Right.
When it comes to distribution bandwidth.
So we were, I mean, it was just a no go.
I mean, like, they just were
like, no, we're not using that.
And so, and that, so we're like, well,
again, let's just figure something else out.
And so we, you know, came up with
this other idea and I, you know,
I'm partial to the new
idea anyway, but the, but pod
love chapters still work fine.
The workaround for the pod
love chapters was, uh,
for feed size was that you use, uh,
paging feed paging so that you,
not all of your episodes are
in a single or in the feed.
So you have a reference to
another file for older episodes.
Okay.
Right.
And, um, yeah, which, which is fine,
but nobody seems to want
to implement that either.
Um, cause that's, that specification has
been around for a long time and it's,
is there a way to, is there a way to
embrace pod love and bring them into the,
into their own tag in the namespace?
No, they've already, yeah, they've already
contributed a lot to the namespace.
Right.
But, but have the actual pod love in the
namespace itself, or is that a problem?
Cause that requires
everyone then to adopt.
The chapters you mean?
Yeah.
The pod love chapters.
No, I don't, I just don't
want to reopen that box.
I mean, it's just done.
All right.
Well, you meant no malice
is what you're saying.
You didn't mean to piss anybody off.
Yeah.
And I just wanted to, I wanted, I
didn't want to talk about, I felt bad.
It's not easy being a
podcaster now, is it?
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
This is what it is.
This is when you get hate mail.
But that there, that is a spec that's
in active use and it's a great spec.
And, uh, that's the other thing
about podcasting 2.0 is it,
all we want is new features.
It doesn't matter where they come from.
Yeah.
They just want cool, cool new features.
So, you know, there's,
there's cool stuff out there.
All of it is stuff that we built here.
No, certainly not.
So anyway, I wanted, that is a, that
is a public service announcement.
Um, yeah.
So you want to, uh, Hey, do
you want to hear my, uh,
you want to hear my Dave Jackson ISO?
Oh yes, of course.
Yeah.
Do, uh, uh, what the heck is a Satoshi?
Oh, oh yes.
What the heck is a Satoshi?
Wait, uh, no, this one's better.
Don't know a thing about crypto.
Uh, okay.
I don't know a thing about crypto.
I don't know a thing about crypto y'all.
Yeah.
No, he's got such a good, that's a
good, a good end of show show there.
Do we want to thank some people?
Uh, yeah.
Uh, this is anything else
you want to talk about?
Um, let me see.
Did we miss anything?
Do we wrap it all up
on the, on the basics?
Cause I think we do need
to thank some people,
but also just briefly talk
about some phase four.
Uh, yeah, we can talk about phase four.
Yeah.
Well, okay.
This is a value for value project.
The whole project.
Uh, I'll read it again
for those who missed it.
The podcast index is here
to preserve, protect,
and extend the open independent
podcasting ecosystem.
We do this by enabling
developers to have access
to open categorized index that will always
be available for free for any use.
Buy a new podcast app today and see
how much better the experience can be.
Screw Coke.
This is new Coke, new podcast apps.com.
Um, so all we asked for in this project
is, uh, you contribute some value back.
If you find it valuable, that
can be done with your time,
your talent, your treasure.
Um, man, we need money to
keep the servers running
for everything for the node to be funded.
And you can do that with your, I rehearsed
this with your fiat fun coupons,
your cuck bucks, or with your satoshis.
We accept all of it.
I go to podcast index.org and the
bottom is a big red donate button.
And let's thank some people
today for supporting the, uh,
the hub of the movement or some hub.
We're something.
I'm not quite sure what we are.
The nucleus.
If, uh, let's see, if we're, if this
is flat earth, we are the North pole.
Yes.
We're the embryo.
Hey, firmament first, baby.
Firmament.
So, uh, yeah.
It's a procedural question here.
Yes.
The age old, like, should
I do these in order?
Should I do these donations
biggest to least in order to get,
to honor the biggest givers up front?
Or should I do them least
to biggest in order
to climax at the end
with the biggest donor?
Well, this is interesting.
The proven model is, uh, is
biggest to, uh, to the smallest.
Okay.
That is the proven model.
Uh, you had me at climax though.
I was interested, like, this could be,
this could be a different way of doing it.
Well, I don't know.
Let's, let's stick with the proven model.
We'll A, B test.
Okay.
Next week we'll do them.
We'll do them.
Okay.
Deal no deliverance.
This is A, everybody.
We're doing version A.
Version A.
Press, click, click on the,
on the graphic in your chapter
mark right now to hear version B.
Uh, be out fun coupons first.
Yes.
Dreb Scott gave us $51.
Dreb, man.
He says.
He's taking, he's taking
sats that everyone's
sending him in and then
putting it back into the show.
Well, you know what he's doing now?
He's, he's, uh, moonlighting
on the, on the, uh,
fun fact Friday podcast
with David, David Medus.
Oh, oh, is he in the
value block over there?
Yes, he is.
And he's, and he's doing chapters?
Yes.
I, he's, he's going to
have a business, man.
I'm telling you, he's
going to have a business.
He's going to get a bunch of, a
bunch of kids to listen to podcasts,
mark the chapters, do the art.
He'll have them chained in a
basement and he's going to be rich.
I tell you, stinking rich.
They don't like a bunch of teenage, a bunch
of teenagers staring at screens all day.
I mean, that's just normal stuff.
Exactly.
They're doing them.
And in fact, he's paying them with, uh,
with sats per chapter they complete.
Yeah.
One set, one set per chapter.
Maybe, maybe, you know, Hey
kid, this is for your future.
They only have to do a hundred
million chapters a year and they,
that can make a living off that.
Yeah.
We're just talking about this
stuff and Bitcoin is over 48,000.
I mean, we were influencing the price.
We, is there, is there
any indication of why?
Cause that jumped up high today.
I don't really understand why.
Um, no, I have no idea.
I could give you a million different
news stories and say, Hey,
it's because of this, but I don't
I think it's, yeah, it's just
look at the curve, you know,
it's got to go back up a hundred
thousand by the end of the year.
And I think that's a fair assessment.
You're seeing a lot of
people agreeing with that.
I don't know why I just,
I, this is what I see.
And I'm like, Oh, that
sounds, sounds reasonable.
Dreb Scott says, uh, says jingles,
go podcasting, uh, see, uh, set, uh,
set streamer note, uh,
Dreb Scott show number donation,
special shout out to the podcast.
Fun fact Friday with Lila and David, not
just fun facts, but also a fun 20 listen.
Dreb.
I love the fun fact Friday show.
I've never listened to it.
Oh, you have to, it's a
dad and his daughter.
That's great.
And, but you know, but they
did everything themselves.
And they also, I think,
I think they put the whole note
together themselves together.
They put their own.
Really?
Yeah.
I believe they got a raspberry
pie and put it all together.
Yeah.
This is, this is really cool.
It's like a, it's like a homeschooling
project that isn't school.
Okay.
And for the, for those developers
and podcasters who, you know, are,
you know, you're in your
twenties right now, this
young lady is probably
going to wind up hiring you for something.
I'm telling you.
Here you go.
Go Dreb.
Thanks, man.
I just downloaded fun fact
Friday into my fountain app.
If that one a shot today, I have
to rotate my apps all the time.
This is a great, great, great podcast.
Thank you, Dreb.
Uh, let's see, uh, Paul Erskine, uh,
he took out a new automatic, uh,
subscription, monthly subscription
for $11 and 14 cents.
I didn't see a note.
Thank you.
From Paul.
Curious about the number.
I like it.
Me too.
Uh, anonymous, $11 and 11 cents,
uh, says, uh, make this anonymous.
Enjoy some fiat fun coupons.
Go podcast.
Woohoo.
Yeah.
Fiat fun coupons.
I throw that in all the time now.
And just like the most normal thing.
And Tina's used to this crap for
me and people, you can see, huh?
What?
Cuck bucks, you know, cuck bucks, huh?
Tina does that too.
Do it with Max's voice.
I've started listening.
It's interesting how Max
releases his episodes.
So he has a full, a full podcast, but
he releases it in parts first and then,
or bits of it, I guess.
And then the full thing.
Is that how I've come to understand this?
Uh, I don't know.
Yeah.
I mean, I, I just will go back
and listen to the old ones.
I haven't listened to anything new.
I've listened to a couple of.
Yeah.
So he'll have, he'll have episode 27,
six, five, four, three, two, one,
and zero is then the full episode.
Oh, okay.
I don't know.
Maybe it's, I think I'm
checking it out in pod verse.
It could just, it could be me
misunderstanding something.
I don't know.
Uh, let's see, uh, survive
at survive from the, uh,
mastodon from podcast index.social.
He gave us, uh, $5 a month subscription.
Thank you very much.
That keeps the whole server running.
Yeah, it does.
Uh, see, those are our Fiat fun coupons.
And so we got some booster grams.
Let's see.
Oh, wow.
Okay.
Kieran from the mere mortals podcast.
I'm, I'm going to be on
that show by the way.
Yes.
I, uh, well, we both saw
this, uh, this boost come in.
They've gone nuts.
They've been, I mean, they're just
boosting everybody everywhere.
Yeah.
Big numbers, big rollers.
A hundred thousand sats.
I think that is a record booster gram.
I think it's a record boost actually.
And holy crap, it worked.
Let's just stop and talk.
Think about that for a second.
The Australian monetary
police are going to
go and find you because you've broken some
sort of law about boosting this and that.
Jacinda's going to like a swim
across the channel in a, in a,
in a hazmat suit and, uh, mess
you up or something like you're,
you're messing everything up down under.
Um, this is, this is
really, uh, let's see.
It says, uh, this is really a message
for everyone in the 2.0 community.
I can't express how much
fun I've had since I
found out about this a mere
one and a half months ago.
I was feeling like I'd
hit a glass ceiling in
terms of the quality I could create for
my shows, but everything
here has well and truly
inspired me to work harder and produce
the best podcasts I can.
Your introduction into
the Bitcoin and lightning
world for me has already
been more than it's
worth its weight in Bitcoin.
Well, uh, let's see.
Would appreciate a
defragmenting to celebrate
my crossing of the $100
fund token threshold
without resorting to the
emasculating cuck bucks.
And, uh, says PS would have boosted more if
the limit was higher on pod friend might
be worth upping that limit, Martin.
That's almost 50 bucks man today.
Yeah.
I've got, so, but the fun, the funny
thing is I don't think of it that way.
I think a hundred thousand Satoshis.
Yeah.
It's like, it never even registers to me.
I know that's, that's what's so crazy.
It's like, I'm already, I'm already
living in that world somehow.
I've got t-shirts.
Uh, I'm behind on t-shirts getting those.
Okay.
Somehow it's an Eric's
got the spreadsheet with
t-shirts in it and they're
all laid out nicely.
It's like name, address,
um, Eric nails that down.
Yeah.
It's, it's beautiful yet somehow this is
mystifying to me and I can't make my,
I can't make myself actually figure
out how to use the spreadsheet.
So I'm an idiot.
I will, I will get these t-shirts,
uh, over to Eric's, uh, this week.
Oh, you need to add entries.
You mean?
Yeah.
I'm like two weeks behind on this.
Oh, okay.
We've been, we've been waiting
over a decade for podcasting 2.0.
I'm sure, you know, everyone will
be able to say, Hey, I was there.
I got the t-shirt.
Remember that?
Eventually.
50,000 sats from Auburn Citadel.
Uh, he says, sup freaks
working my way to a t-shirt.
I appreciate, I appreciate your work
on freedom enabling technology.
It's so important in this crazy world.
So what do we set as a
Satoshi number for t-shirts?
It's a hundred dollars
in, uh, Fiat fun coupons.
I don't know what, what's,
uh, what's the limit?
Well, I mean, because the number
will fluctuate, but I think that we,
you know, let's just start
living in the sat world, right?
Yeah.
We need a hard limit, like
irrespective of whatever.
Somehow 250 sounds good,
but 200 would be okay.
Two in a thousand or 250.
Let's do 200.
200?
It's the lower one.
Okay.
200.
Uh, uh, the, uh, t-shirt committee
may adjust this number later.
T-shirt committee.
Which is.
Not when it goes down, but you
know, we know you won't be,
won't be sending us 200,000 at some point.
The t-shirt committee.
Here's a car.
The t-shirt committee is Eric sending us
a message like, y'all are full of crap.
Exactly.
Oh yeah.
Eric.
You're right.
We need to be careful because he's,
Eric is figuring out counting tax,
all of this stuff, which,
which is going to be something we'll
be able to share, provide, et cetera.
But.
Yeah.
I know what he's going to say.
He's going to be like 250,000 sats
is the shipping amount to Australia.
You idiots.
Okay.
All right.
Yes, sir.
Yes.
Greg, Greg Thomas, uh,
gave us 10,804 sats.
He says, Adam and Dave, I've been a
monthly PayPal donor for a while,
but now I'll be canceling that
donation in favor of booster grams.
Still donating.
Just not in cut books.
Go podcasting.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Go podcasting.
Um, dude, there's so many of these.
Good God almighty.
Well, we're going to have to
have a cutoff at some point.
That's just.
I don't like cutoffs though.
So.
Yeah.
Well, it's sad.
It's okay.
As long as you don't mind five hour shows.
Uh, Michael Moritzon.
Michael.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Boost.
Michael Moritzon.
From the, from the kingdom of Denmark.
Yeah.
The polygamist from Denmark.
The poly...
He gave us, um, uh, 5,277 sats and it
says mandatory boost for mentioning me.
Yes.
All right.
Boost.
Uh, Aaron at Cellonomics.
Uh, he gave us 2,000, uh, 2,000
sats and he says five words.
Episode 50 was a boost of bukkake.
Ah, that's where I got it from.
That's where I got it from.
This is a family show.
Yes.
Oh, bad, bad man.
Bad man.
You've influenced me very negatively.
I apologize profusely.
I'm, I'm really working on myself.
Uh, Brian of Hive gave us
1,000 sats and he says,
and that's when he pointed out why one
of Hive's best apps is
called Hive Keychain.
Brian, I have to admit, I have no
idea what you're talking about.
Hive Keychain.
That's where you keep all of
your, all of your keys, I guess.
But why is that one of Hive's best apps?
I mean, I guess it would
be the most important.
Well, now, now, did, did
you look at the timestamp?
Dude.
By the way, these, I expect these emails
to come in with a clip, you know,
just click on the, uh, click on the link
and it goes right to that time code.
I mean, if you're going to expect that, why
not just expect it to have an MP3 of the
clip attached to it?
I didn't want to take away
your weekend, but okay.
I'm not saying I'm going to build it.
I'm just thinking about this.
Oh, okay.
That's a, that's called a touche.
Um, let's see.
Boostergram, 1,000 sats from Chad Farrow.
Sending my first
Boostergram from Fountain.
Go podcasting.
Yes, indeed.
Go podcasting!
Uh, let's see.
Chad Farrow had another 1,000 sats.
Hey, Adam, are these Boostergrams just
a Trojan horse to get podcasters to add
donation sections to their podcast?
No, it's, it's a feature to feature
to enhance the donation segments.
That's the whole point.
And when you watch, you
watch what happens when
you start to do your Boostergram corner.
This stuff, this stuff
really, really works.
It's not a Trojan horse.
We're coming at full front.
Yeah, no secrets here, brah.
Yeah.
No secrets.
Uh, Stephen B said, check it out.
Sender ID is being sent now.
And I see in the debug section
that it is being sent.
Very nice.
Say something else about,
you know, if these were, um,
these were Booster comments, yeah,
you can, you can treat like a
hundred thousand can go to the top.
Oh.
I'm just, I'm just gamifying stuff,
you know, it's in my nature.
Yeah.
You could, you can like,
uh, like an auction almost.
You guys top somebody or whatever.
Something like.
Like a leaderboard.
Leaderboard.
Yeah.
Stuff like that.
Oscar Mary says, uh, you
really have released a beast.
Boosting is addictive.
One thousand sats.
Uh, oh, and he said, uh,
Oscar said, it worked.
I guess that must've been his first boost.
Yes.
From Fountain.
Um, he said, uh, don't worry
about reading all my boosts.
No, I'm going to read every one of them.
By the way, for, um, wait, let me
see what the most recent one is.
I thought I got a, I was going to
look at, cause what I like so much,
we have a daily, uh, a daily thing.
And we look at how many transactions
each app, each app is doing.
I love, I'm looking for
the most recent one.
I love that.
It's okay.
Just keep, keep going.
I'm, I'm just, I'm just, I'm just, uh, Oscar
had another, uh, he gave us a, he gave
us a boost for mentioning
Fountain on the show.
Ah.
The 1,000 sats.
See how that works.
Mm-hmm.
Here we go.
Sphinx this past, what was
it, day had 661 transactions.
Is this, yeah, this, oh,
you've, or you've ordered it.
How nice.
I don't think, I don't think
it's sorted properly though.
Oh, it, but it's sort, it looks like
it's sorted by amount of transactions,
which is what I, that's what I want.
I think that's a coincidence.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Sphinx 661, Podfriend 339, Breeze
351, CurioCaster 130, Fountain 112,
Unknown 46, Podverse
3, but they're still
in beta testing stuff.
This is, this is real,
I really love this because it's not
necessarily equal to the amount of Satoshis
that come through per, per transactions.
Transaction amount, uh, going through
the system is, is really off the chart.
So Fountain, with 112 transactions,
um, Is that today's report?
Just today, yeah.
It was 48,699 sats came through Fountain.
There's 400,000 transactions
in our node database.
This is crazy.
And that's since, that's
really since December.
When Mac said he was,
he always said the only thing he's
really worried about is that we
break the Lightning Network.
He might not be kidding.
I mean, we're learning about
compacting databases already.
Yeah.
I asked, I asked him, uh, uh, Tim, I was
like, what, um, uh, when, how often do you
compact your database?
And he said, uh, I don't, I'm scared.
Yeah, exactly.
Well, voltage has a setting for it.
Yeah.
Um, yeah.
Graham at voltage said he was good there.
He said they're working on a
document that shows how to tend,
how to back your stuff up
and tend your database.
So they're, they're going to,
they're going to put that out
as like a support document and
that'll be good for everybody.
Yeah.
Good.
That's crazy.
Good node hygiene.
Oscar Mary again, 777 sats.
He said it's time for the board
meeting booster gram week.
Indeed.
It is booster gram week.
Yeah.
He says, uh, so he's got another one for
1000 sats and he says it does not stop.
No, it doesn't.
It just keeps going.
Uh, thousand sats from Kevin Bay.
And he says, I sent a booster
gram using curio caster,
but it didn't seem to make it.
Did this one get through?
Yes, it did.
Yes.
Now who else was, was there
a new app that was the,
just started sending value for value?
Uh, you're thinking of cast a
Matic and he's still testing.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
He's in beta.
And who is, who is that?
Uh, it's Franco Solerio.
Okay.
Yeah.
Franco, let me know when you
need, when, when you're ready.
Cause I want to promote
it on the no agenda.
Yeah.
And he, and, uh, that's a really good app.
I don't, uh, I've seen it.
Yeah.
And it's, it's iOS only, right?
No, I, in fact, I think I talked
about it on the last show.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
It's a really, it's a
really good app on iOS.
Uh, let's see.
Uh, James Cridland, 950 sats.
And he says, a really useful
interview and enjoying the show.
Listening, listening in a non-boost app.
So I popped over here to leave
you this boost in pod friend.
Yeah.
Very good.
Thank you.
Uh, let's see.
Uh, okay.
950 sats from Sir Bill.
He said, don't read this on the air.
Okay.
All right.
Uh, okay.
Wish granted.
Uh, Mary, uh, Oscar Mary gave us 777 sats
and he says, crinkle paper for me, baby.
Oh, wait, I'm sorry.
I, I, I talked over.
I talked over.
Go do it.
Crinkle again.
Okay.
All right.
Well, he's got to follow up with
another seven, seven, seven, seven.
He says, he says, I do like this podcast.
Here's your cue to boost.
You know, you want to go anonymous
ASMR on demand, anonymous, 500 sats.
And the message is, I'm sorry.
You're in PHP all the time.
Me too.
There's so many of these.
I want to hit reply to.
I know that's the thing that's missing.
Yeah.
Reply button.
Another one from anonymous
and it's 475 sats.
And the message is freedom.
Oh, wait, I have that one.
Do you?
Yeah.
Oh, is that a jingle?
Okay.
It's a fan favorite.
That's our next, our next president.
Okay.
Um, let's see.
333 sats from podcast junkies.
Says Harry from podcast
junkies via fountain.
Boost.
And, uh, see bootstrap bandit.
That's Tim K from LNP.
Yep.
Uh, he sent us a hundred sats
and he just says, holla.
And, uh, there is 95 sats from, and the
name of this person is dirty message.
And the message is a sequence of emojis
that I cannot describe on the air.
Okay.
Well, we have to up our sats so
we don't get offended by the,
those emojis in the future.
Yeah.
And set the limit at 96 sats.
Yep.
That's right.
That'll, that'll show them.
Uh, that's the end of the booster grams
and monthly donors is, uh, let's see.
Keith Gibson gave us $50.
Thank you, Keith.
Uh, sir, Alex Gates.
Is he a sir?
Is he on the note?
He is now.
Okay.
$25.
Uh, Tim Hudgens, uh, my
buddy, Tim, uh, good guy.
$25.
Uh, let's see.
Paul Saltzman gave us $22.22.
Yeah.
That's his, his, his regular number.
Mm-hmm.
I wish I knew, I guess it's just
a double, double, uh, snake eyes.
Yeah.
He means it well, regardless.
Jeremy Cavanaugh gave us $10.
Dwayne Goldie gave us $8.
Jeremy Gerds gave us $5
and Thomas Sullivan Jr.
gave us $5 and David Woodfine gave us $3.
And that's lovely.
And we really appreciate, um, all of
the support that we've been receiving.
The monetary support is key.
Um, in fact, we're, uh,
we're going to start, uh,
adding some more things
that will cost more money.
Yeah.
We'll, we'll talk about it.
Uh, but for now, I mean, holy
crap, this thing is running.
We've got like a perpetual motion machine.
It just kind of hunkers ahead.
You know, the flywheel never stops.
It's one of the most amazing things.
Thank you all so much for supporting it.
Uh, and this is the whole project,
podcastindex.org, podcastindex.social,
the GitHub, uh, supporting,
uh, the machines.
We have, I think 20 servers
running now, um, legal help.
We've, uh, we've, we've, uh, engaged
some lawyers, you know, like low,
low hundred dollars,
but for stuff that we just,
we're trying to make this all work
and make it work for everybody.
And that includes people who
are interested in advertising.
Don't be shy.
Step up y'all.
Um, but you can, um,
that's not our income.
We are more interested in, uh,
you thinking about what kind of value
you get from the whole project.
Just turn that into a number
that's meaningful to you and, uh,
go to podcastindex.org
and send us your fun fiat
coupons on the red donut donate button.
Or you can go ahead and boost
right now, get a new, uh,
podcast app, newpodcastapps.com.
Have some fun.
Join the, join the cool kids.
Um, you want to do a
little bit of namespace?
Yes, I'd love to.
I'd love to.
So I think what I'm going to do
over the next week before, uh,
the end of the month is go ahead and
write everything up for the new tags,
uh, as best I can.
And then we'll just start hashing on them.
And so what I think it is right now,
I think it'll be initially, uh, live.
And, um, medium.
Right.
So we, so we can determine,
uh, whether it's video.
Uh, yeah.
What, what format it takes.
And, um, and I have something
to say about that in a second.
And then, uh, this new one that, uh,
just popped up is called, is, um,
the idea of pinning episodes.
And so, or what you call
like gateway episodes.
And so you've, I think you
commented on that issue.
Yes.
The pin, the pinned, uh, pinned episodes.
Yeah.
And I think that's a great idea.
I think it's good enough to try
to get it in, into phase four.
Let me, yeah, well, let
me, um, I don't know.
I'd have to hear everything,
but what I like about the idea is especially
for long, longer lasting podcast,
uh, like the no agenda show, but
even, um, even this podcast there,
there could be episodes that either.
Hey, you know, listen
to this episode, which,
and we did a couple of those on no agenda.
You know, we call them the 0.5 episodes.
So we did one at 100.5, 200.5.
And I think maybe three or 400.5.
And we recap, it's kind of like an onion
where we, we bring in things from the,
from the previous 100
point something episode.
And it really brings people up to
speed on, uh, on a lot of the basics.
And I think a lot of podcasts are like
that and there's people always suggest
different things and it could, or it could
just be, you know, like a telegram group.
Just, and here's an important episode
that you need to make sure you heard.
I mean, no matter what your reason is,
I really liked the idea of pinning.
Yeah.
And I mean, even for this show,
it is hard to go back and
suggest now that somebody
listened to the very first episode.
Right.
Because it has changed so much.
Yeah.
A lot of people, this, this behavior is,
I've never understood it, but it's rampant.
People often will go back and start
an entire podcast from the beginning.
And, and I can't explain what it is,
but it's every single podcast
I've ever been involved in.
People have done that.
That's interesting.
Cause I, I'm, I would call
myself a neurotic completist.
So I'm the guy that will, I
can't just read like a book.
I've got to read the entire series,
even if it's 50 books, you know,
and I have that neuroses,
but I don't have this,
but I don't have this urge to go back and
listen to every episode of a podcast.
That's, that's like something that's,
that's a different thing, I guess.
I don't know.
But I mean, if you had the gateway episode
idea in place, you could just say,
okay, this is a great onboard into
our show at this, like at this point.
And it could, it could be from like a
year ago, but at least it gives you like,
this is the good, this
is the best entry point.
And it just kind of floats in
the feed along with every other,
along with all the current stuff.
It's, it's critical that we get podcasters
involved in these types of discussions.
Cause I'm really going off of what I've
learned from having podcast audiences for,
you know, for 18 years or whatever.
There's a, there's a whole bunch of things
we're missing as a group because we just
don't have a lot of people who
are in there are also podcasters.
There's just so much
stuff that is unexpected.
Like even just the importance
of, you know, comments,
which has been a big one for us.
That's, we're going to learn things that
we never expected, but we need that.
We need kind of the feedback
from the podcasters.
And it's kind of, you know,
not everyone's like, Oh yeah,
I'll go on this GitHub thing.
That's intuitive for me
because it's not strangely.
Um, the other, the other thing that the
other tag that I'd like to get through there
is a recommendations.
And it's not that a lot of people
have been clamoring for this,
but I think that, uh, Benjamin
Bellamy and his group has done a lot.
They've done a lot of work on this.
It's clearly something
that they need and want.
Yep.
And I think that is all that matters.
So, um, once that thing
gets into the spec,
then it becomes a little bit more visible
to people in the industry and they can
look at it and maybe they find
out that they need it also.
But it's a very big, it's a very big tag.
And, uh, so I think that people have been
a little nervous about it because of the
size and the scope of it.
I mean, if the way I understood it,
when we had Benjamin on is it's something
that the podcaster can control, uh,
much like chapters or could have an, uh,
a trusted third party
manage that for them,
which actually gives a lot of advertising
slash marketing opportunities.
People pay attention.
That's exactly right.
And to me, it sounds
like a fantastic idea.
I liked it.
Cause I immediately wanted a
system that, that, you know,
does a lot of that for me that I can, you
know, but I want to have control over it.
I don't know.
I like chapters.
It's to me, it's exactly like that.
Oh, here's, you know, but I want to
recommend podcasting 2.0, MoFax,
uh, DH unplugged.
Uh, but you know, I'll probably a
pod land, uh, orange pill, you know,
I don't know how many I
can do, but I like it.
I think that that's a great way to, to build
out these networks in the tribe model.
That's almost like, you know, here are
my affiliated tribes today, you know,
cause I might want to scalp them tomorrow.
I look at it, I look at it like a
little bit like alternative enclosure.
It's a thing that needs,
should be there because it's got a lot
of care behind it and it's got a lot.
And it doesn't matter that nobody's
going to use it on day one.
That doesn't matter.
What matters is that it's well
thought out and it's a good idea.
And so it can be in the spec.
It's fine.
There's things, things
can be in the spec that,
that people don't just immediately
jump on because six months from now,
somebody may find it and be like,
yeah, this is, this is good.
So I'm, I'm on board with that now.
So I think it's good and
very diplomatic to reach
out to our socialist friends that way.
I do too.
I mean, they don't have much over there.
You gotta, I mean, you
gotta give them everything.
No, we'll, we'll, we'll let them
into the namespace into phase four,
but only if they have a vaccine passport.
No.
Just kidding.
Ben, just kidding.
Benjamin.
I'm riffing because it's messed up, man.
The whole world has gone crazy.
The, so the medium tag.
That goes along with
live basically, right?
It can.
Yeah, it can.
It's a, it's a, it's a
way to signal to the app.
And I think we've talked
about this before.
It's a way to signal to the app
what type of content this is.
Is it a video?
Um, is it meant, is it a audio book?
Is it a, is it a music, an album
of music, blah, blah, blah.
So I've got already, uh,
I think I told you a couple of
weeks ago that my son is a, is a
bass player in a metal band and, um,
that I was going to release
his album as a podcast.
Right.
And I did, so it's on the index.
Oh, you didn't ping me about that.
I did not.
I was, I'm surprising you on the show.
Oh, okay.
Uh, the name, you can just search
on it in the index or any of the,
any of the apps that use us for search.
Apple podcast, Spotify, or wherever
you get your podcast from.
Yes.
Wherever you get your, uh,
your new podcast apps from wherever
you get your podcasting 2.0
apps, you can, uh, search for that.
It's called, the album is Torcon
that know the name of the band.
And I, please don't ask
me what this means.
I got no idea.
These guys are teenagers.
Torcon 7, T-O-R-C-O-N.
And then just the number seven.
Um, and it's still like two words.
So if you search in there, you'll see
the podcast and it's just an album.
Wait, wait, T-O-R-C-A-N?
T-O-R-C-O-N.
C-O-N space seven, uh, seven V-1-1, bro.
Yeah, but it's still, it's still
works with the number two.
And the first track I
have here is Super Tramp.
Yeah, that can, uh, yeah, I
don't know how it ordered them.
It ordered them out, it's weird,
but I don't think they care
what the track order is.
Um, so that's the, that's the
album and it uses the medium tag.
Ah, how did he get the medium tag?
I hand coded the feed.
That's my audition for the band.
Can't wait to listen to that.
I love that.
That's cool.
Yeah.
It's a thrash metal band.
They boost them.
Boost.
So the way, and the way it's set up
is there's four, uh, value blocks.
I've tried to make this, uh.
Oh my goodness.
I love this, Dave.
This is great.
You're, you're like,
uh, Layla and her dad.
You're, you're, you're doing
it with the thrash metal kid.
Love it.
Yeah.
Each one of them, the drummer, the bass
player, the guitar player, and, uh, the,
the singer, they all, each one
of them has an LNP wallet.
And so they each have a split.
Oh man, that's so cool.
So you can boost them all.
Uh, but anyway, the,
the medium tag is in there and I
thought this would be a good way
for people to test out against this because
what should happen in this scenario,
the medium tag should say is music.
So what, what the app
would be expected to do
is display this in a way that makes sense
as a, as a, as if you were in
Spotify or some music play.
Right.
Which it doesn't do yet.
The app I use doesn't do it.
Obviously it does.
It, in fact, it only has, it
doesn't have any show notes.
It just has a title, I think.
So anyway, that's a test
podcast that people
can use to try to see
what their app can do
with this sort of functionality.
And, uh, so that's a great idea.
That's a great idea.
And I'll try to put a
couple of more of these
test feeds in there because I think for a
feature like this test feed is a, is a
great way to, you need something to,
to bounce against and see what, yeah.
And get the kids working for the
organization, you know, they're so useless.
Otherwise do something.
I mean, I'm keeping all the money.
Of course.
Are you in, are you in the split or you
foolishly just put the kids in there?
Oh man.
No, I'm an idiot.
I put the kids in there.
I love that.
Very cool.
Very, very cool.
So I think that's the, um,
I think that's, that's,
that'll get us started and then we
can add, you know, I think we'll have
room for, you know, one or two more tags,
but I feel good about that so far.
If somebody else has a form with that
or, or think something different,
you know, get me up.
And so kind of our schedule now is you're
finishing up some stuff, uh, with Eric for
the accounting and then we're going
to spruce up, um, the onboarding.
Uh, yeah.
Yeah.
That's the plan.
Cause we've, it's coming up, uh,
it's getting close or it's getting
further on into the end of the year.
And so at some point we're going to, I mean
like the, all those sats that have come
into the, to the podcast index
node, I mean, that's income.
So we got to declare it and we got
to do all the right stuff by taxes.
So I had to sort of hit
pause on development
and then go and build this reporting, uh,
for Eric so that we can, you know, be
legally compliant and all those things.
And when, as soon as I'm done
with that, I'll be back.
But I did have time though.
I did sandwich in the per
episode value blocks.
I saw that.
I love it.
And, uh, hopefully my new RSS,
uh, Curio, what did he call it?
It was still CurioCaster, right?
Right.
He didn't have a different
name for it, did he?
Yeah.
That's right.
It's truly a CurioCaster.
So, well.
Hopefully I'll get episode
blocks in there soon then.
Uh, Gigi is a well-known, uh, Bitcoiner.
Sure.
Um, he, uh, wrote a famous book in Bitcoin
world called 21 lessons and, um, he,
uh, did
all the sort of code review and, um, uh,
on the value block spec on the namespace.
Right, right, right.
And he, he wrote up the per, uh,
that per episode part of the spec.
He, he did, he, he really
has helped me over the
last month and a half to revise that thing
because he really wants this.
What, what were the main things that,
uh, that he added or, or adjusted?
It, it was just wording.
It was just, it was really
just wording and finding, uh,
some inconsistencies with the
way things were described.
It was really just a lot of, uh,
uh, like the whole organization.
Yeah.
Restrict yourself to only
the value spec, please.
Uh, but anyway, he, uh, so he,
he cleaned all that up and,
and made it, it's final now.
It's, it's a good spec.
And, uh, what that means is
we can go ahead and put in,
we can finalize the value
block in phase four now.
And it has, it has per episode
splits in it, uh, in the first feed.
And the only feed currently
that has per episode
value blocks is closing
the loop, which is the
put out by the company that he works for.
And they have, uh, actually their,
uh, second to last episode,
they had Paul Etoy from stack work on it.
Oh, really?
Oh, cool.
Yeah.
And each, each one of those episodes,
like that episode with Paul
has Paul in the split.
Oh, and so this is sort
of really outstanding.
So this, there's two things that are,
I think are the future and you know,
that you and I will be
working really closely on.
It's the splits, which, you know, when
you position it in a different light,
it's really digital royalties
of the future direct from, uh,
value return directly for value received.
Um, and I was going to make such a
deep point about the second thing.
We're going long.
You're getting, you're wearing down.
No, it was, uh, it was
the, it was the split.
Oh, and the medium tag.
Oh yeah.
The medium tag, because
I was only thinking in
ways of different types
of medium, but, uh,
music is so distinct and that
triggering, you know, hold on a second,
that triggering, um, a signal to an app
that the app knows, hold on a second.
This is a piece of music
and I can change the
way I'm displaying information or certain
information would be relevant or not.
I can actually change
the interface to this.
I say, do you realize how
revolutionary that can be?
This is one of the most important
episodes we've ever done.
We've invented everything.
That's your title.
Including Firm and First, Flat Earth.
Yes.
Good to go.
Um, I mean.
You feel me though?
I mean, how important that is.
No, I feel you a hundred,
I feel you a hundred percent
because the first thing I think of
is, uh, Random Access Memories,
that, that album by Daft Punk.
So that album has, uh, quite a few tracks.
Maybe 75% of the tracks have
a guest artist on the track.
Oh yeah, you know, there was
lawsuits over, over that album.
Oh really?
Oh my goodness.
It's like all kinds of
lawsuits because it had
so many people attributed to it and still
there were samples that,
that were left out.
And as we say in the music business,
when you have a hit, you get the writ.
Oh yeah.
People just sue you.
Hey, that sounds like my song, man.
Vanilla Ice, come here.
Yeah.
That, um, see, so that album, just
take, simplifying it down to,
it was Daft Punk and one, and one
guest artist on this, on this
track, there's your splits.
Exactly.
And then they're getting royalties
in perpetuity from every,
every single time that, yeah,
that episode is listened to.
Exactly.
There's, boom, done.
But, I mean, I just don't,
I don't want to push ahead,
but when you get a guy that is
so, was it Alex Gates who's been
pushing for the medium tag?
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Documenting, documenting.
You're doing, you're doing a good job on
this because you told me this morning,
I have to document this stuff.
Medium tag.
Did he, uh, did he come up with it?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, he did.
Good.
We call that inventor.
Inventor.
Get absolutely nothing with it,
except at least they don't
misquote you 20 years from
now or you get screwed up.
That's the thing that I hated the most.
No.
Excuse me.
The marriage of those two things.
I stopped smoking, so
it's all coming out now.
The marriage of those
two things is beautiful.
Yeah.
Because, you know, that's
where we get into,
we can finally do Mark Hall
justice with a documentary,
just so we could tell the app, hey,
display this maybe in a 16
by 9 or in big in the window
or anything like that, you know,
the way you might expect a
documentary to run, which
would mean probably, you know,
default with, uh, with chapters.
I don't know.
I mean, I'm just shooting from
the hip now, but, and then music,
you know, categorize
it by, um, or sort it in
this particular fashion.
Oh my God, that is so cool.
Yeah.
You build, you, you build the,
you build the base layer.
And then you, you can do book
and then audio book PDF.
All of a sudden your app is showing
a PDF with a great interface to,
to browse through a book or an audio book.
What we're, what we're doing now is building
the base layer for what's coming next.
Which is, they have no
idea what's coming next.
Which is.
Or what is coming next cannot be stopped.
This is, this is a QAnon thing.
Oh, is that a phrase from QAnon?
Yeah, it's like W-I-C-N-C, or S-C-B.
Oh, this is too complicated.
Oh yeah, I know.
It's like, yeah, where
we go one, we go all,
but it's now what is
coming cannot be stopped.
And that's, that's true.
I believe now with everything I'm
seeing, the momentum cannot be stopped.
Apple is to be ignored at this point.
The listeners are, listeners
are checking out other apps.
They're not, they're
not standing for this.
They're not standing for hours of delay.
What?
Um.
ISO information war.
We are in an information war.
I'm going to cut that down, so
there's less of a, less of a gap.
This, this, this is from,
uh, like Australian news.
This thing is, I'm, I'm in
love with Australian news.
Whatever, I have no idea
what they're talking
about or whatever all
this stuff is going on
locally, but it's, it's like incredible.
The guy has this amazing voice and
then they read headlines and tweets.
And other amazing voices.
Like, um, so there, there's a
clip, Australia reading headlines.
Play that one.
Is this, uh, uh, where do
you watch this on YouTube?
Yeah.
It's some YouTube video.
I think James linked to it,
but I can't, I can't stop.
I watched like three or four of them.
Hold on a second.
I boosted a little bit here.
Multiple greyhound track upgrades,
renew focus on animal welfare.
It's like they, there, there's
a, that was about great.
That was the word greyhound,
uh, dog track racing.
Yeah.
They're like saying a news story.
I think it's one of these shows
that like analyzes the news.
Of course.
It's a joke.
Analyzes the media.
Yeah.
And so then they, they show the,
the tweet and they read it in
these super dramatic voices.
And, uh, like ISO hiding
the truth, uh, do that one.
Okay.
Hold on a second.
Government and the media
are hiding the truth.
It's like, there's a, there's
like a million of these.
I just had to make myself stop.
Oh no.
Yeah.
It's fantastic.
Well, I, I get different Australian
news and none of it's good.
They just got another six weeks
of restrictions and some.
Where's that at?
In Sydney?
Sydney.
Yeah.
New South Wales.
Man.
That stinks.
Yeah.
They had, wow, this, the, the zero
COVID policy is a tough nut to crack.
You know?
Oh man.
I feel sorry for those guys.
We know a lot of people in Australia.
Hell yeah.
Oh yeah.
I feel, I feel sorry
that they, that they're,
can't get out and go visit
the rest of the world.
Um, anyway, you got anything else?
Uh, no, I, I think that's pretty,
we've, we've done a good job together.
Uh, so next week we're still
trying to figure it out.
I'm going to the Netherlands
will be the first
time I've seen my daughter in 18 months.
I'm really excited about that.
Uh, her birthday is on the 27th.
That is Friday.
So we're going to see if we can figure
something out where we might have to,
uh, skip one board meeting.
And then after that, we got a cool,
a couple of cool guests coming up.
Yeah.
We've got, uh, do we want to say
or just leave it as a surprise?
Leave it as a surprise.
Okay.
All right.
Yeah.
They'll, they'll see you in
the minutes from this meeting.
My lips are sealed.
All right, Dave, have
a great weekend, man.
All right, man.
You too.
Okay.
All right, everybody.
Thank you so much for
attending the board meeting.
Podcasting 2.0.
We'll be here next week or the week after.
You're all welcome.
See you then.
Take care.
Podcasting 2.0.
Visit podcastindex.org
for more information.
I don't know a thing about crypto.
Okay.